Guide to the Professor John Lienhard Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Engines of Our Ingenuity Talks
  - Brief History of Power Production, A, 7/17/92 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Many Faces of an Academician, The, 8/28/92 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Peerless Type-M Gas Odorizer - ASME Landmark, 9/10/92 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - About Darwin, Gaia, and the Networks, 9/10/92 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reflections on Competition and Cooperation, 9/15/92 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Reflections on Competition and Cooperation, 9/16/92 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cooperation and Communication: Darwin, Gaia, and the Computer Nets, 9/18/92 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Reading Japan in America's Past: A Search for America's Future, 9/21/92 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Competition and Cooperation: Darwin, Gaia, and the Computer Nets, 9/27/92 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Darwin and Gaia: Reflections on Competition and Cooperation:, 9/28/92 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - In Response to Tom West's "In The Mind's Eye", 10/3/92 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Creativity in Science and Engineering, 10/28/92 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Women and the Healing Arts: Gaining an Education - Finding a Place, 10/30/92 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Killing the First Person, 11/5/92 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Cooperation and Competition, 11/10/92 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Cooperation and Competition: Joining the Information Revolution, 11/11/92 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Feedback, Clockwork, Computation, and Revolution, 11/14/92 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Cooperation and Competition in the Communications Revolution, 11/22/92 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Research Showcase - Moderator's Script, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Eye of the Forehead: Eye of the Mind, 1/12/93 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Cooperation, Completion, and the Communication Revolution, 1/31/93 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Power and the Changing Face of America, 2/2/93 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Looking Inside the Inventive Mind, 2/13/93 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Eye of the Forehead: From Alchemy to Modern Science, The, 2/17/93 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Cooperation, Competition, and the Communications Revolution, 2/24/93 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - On Making the Engines of Our Ingenuity, 2/25/93 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - On Making the Engines of Our Ingenuity, 2/26/93 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Success, Failure, and Scientific Literacy, 3/25/93 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Thomas Jefferson and a New American Technology, 4/15/93 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 4/17/93 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - In Which We Communicate, Cooperate, and Make Revolution, 4/18/93 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Feedback and Freedom: Controlling Processes & Controlling Ourselves, 5/5/93 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Cooperation and Competition: Darwin, Gaia, and the Computer Nets, 5/5/93 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Where Do Ideas Come From?, 5/6/93 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Communication, Community, and the Electronic Networks, 5/12/93 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Creativity in Engineering, 5/18/93 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Thoughts for an Honors Banquet, 5/20/93 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 5/27/93 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - On Making the Engines of Our Ingenuity, 5/31/93 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Roads Out of Town, The, 6/10/93 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Electric Words, Electric Thoughts: The Electric Sparks of Change, 6/17/93 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Riding the Information Revolution, 6/18/93 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Romantic Poets and 19th Century Engineering, The, 6/21/93 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Engines of Communication, 6/23/93 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - On Making the Engines of Ingenuity, 6/30/93 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Surfing the Sea of Stories, 7/1/93 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - What Is a Bachelor's Degree?, 8/3/93 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Thoughts for an Award Ceremony, 8/10/93 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 9/9/93 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Thoughts on Pictures and Revolutions, 10/8/93 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Communication and Technological Revolution, 10/12/93 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Tunnel Walled and Overlaid - With Dazzling Crystal, A, 10/23/93 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Reflections on Communications as a Revolution: What are We in For?, 10/29/93 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Concern About Dysfunction in University Research, A, 11/3/93 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Of Otters and the Ik, 11/7/93 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Equations of State and Spinodal Lines, 11/18/93 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tyndall and the Romantic Agenda, 12/8/93 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Electric Words, Electric Thoughts: The Electric Sparks of Change, 12/9/93 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Of Otters and the Ik: Communication and the Community, 12/12/93 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden, 1/2/94 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Reflections on the Nature of Technological Change, 2/3/94 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dragon In the Cliff: Women and 19th Century Science, A, 2/8/94 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - We Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 2/19/94 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Community and Environment: Writing Equations For Our Survival, 2/24/94 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Tom West Introduction, 3/3/94 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tyndall and the Romantic Agenda, 3/8/94 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Internal Eye, External Eye, and the Child's Eye, 3/18/94 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Tunnel Walled and Overlaid - With Dazzling Crystal, A, 3/31/94 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Where do Ideas Come From?, 4/5/94 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Conversation on Community, Change, and the Wellspring of Ideas, A, 4/7/94 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Making the Familiar Strange: Reflections on the Origins of Ideas, 4/9/94 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Community and Environment: Writing Equations For Our Survival, 4/12/94 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - On Making the Engines of Our Ingenuity, 4/20/94 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Reflections and Conclusion, 4/21/94 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Making the Familiar Strange: Reflections on the Origins of Ideas, 4/28/94 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Visual Technologies and the New Science, 4/28/94 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 1: In God's Image, 5/1/94 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 5/6/94 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 2, 5/8/94 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - We Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 5/13/94 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 3, 5/15/94 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dragon in the Cliff, A, 5/16/94 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Communication and the Road Out of the Eden - Part 4, 5/22/94 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - We Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 5/25/94 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - We Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 5/25/94 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 5/26/94 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Dragon in the Cliff, A, 6/21/94 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - John Tyndall and the Romantic Agenda, 7/24/94 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - In Which John Tyndall makes the Familiar Strange, 7/26/94 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Conversation with Pieter Laurens Mol, A, 8/27/94 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - We Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 9/1/94 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 1: In God's Image, 9/12/94 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 2, 9/19/94 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Once Upon a Time, 9/21/94 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Eye of the Forehead, Eye of the Mind, 9/24/94 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Looking Inside the Inventive Mind, 9/28/94 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Communication and the Road Out of Eden - Part 4, 10/3/94 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Future of the Print Media, The, 10/5/94 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Reflections on Information, Biology, and Community, 10/6/94 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - I Dressed the Wound, But God Healed Him, 10/7/94 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Making The Familiar Strange, 10/20/94 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 10/22/94 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 10/27/94 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Making the Familiar Strange, 10/28/94 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Dragon in the Cliff, A, 11/15/94 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Imagining the Future, 11/17/94 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 11/28/94 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Images of the 19th Century - Part 1, 12/4/94 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - On Making the Engines of Our Ingenuity, 12/8/94 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Community, Anarchy, and Environment, 1/19/95 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Future of the Print Media, The, 1/24/95 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Science, Invention, and You, 2/2/95 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Resurrecting the First Person, 2/10/95 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - On the Occasion of the 1000th Engines Episode, 2/14/95 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Looking Inside the Inventive Mind, 2/16/95 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Stories of Some Black Inventors & Technologists, The, 2/22/95 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Looking For Leagues Under the Sea, 2/25/95 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Images of the 19th Century, 3/2/95 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Dragon in the Cliff, A, 3/5/95 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Community and Environment: Writing Equations for Our Survival, 3/16/95 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Finding the Objective Eye: Leonardo To Versalius, 3/21/95 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Community and the Internet, 3/30/95 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Dragon in the Cliff, A, 4/5/95 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Seeing Through A Child's Eyes, 4/13/95 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - How We Finally Wiped the Smile of Reason From Our Faces, 4/18/95 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 4/21/95 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Jane Marcet and Her Circle, 4/22/95 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Who Am I?, 4/25/95 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Future of the Print Media, The, 4/27/95 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 5/4/95 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Community Anarchy and the Environment, 5/8/95 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Machines as Metaphor, 5/15/95 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Commencement Address, 5/20/95 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - On Making the Familiar Strange, 5/28/95 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Commencement Address, 6/1/95 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 6/8/95 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Brief History of Power Production, A, 6/16/95 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Reflection on Business and Invention, A, 6/22/95 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Future of the Print Media, The, 7/27/95 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Comments, 8/16/95 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - On Making the Familiar Strange, 8/17/95 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Faculty Salute to Dr. Pickering, 8/23/95 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Invisible Technology, 9/10/95 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Community, Anarchy and the Environment, 9/13/95 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Community, Anarchy and the Environment, 9/19/95 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Future of Design: A Question of Visualization, The, 9/20/95 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Internal Eye, External Eye and Making Museums, 9/26/95 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Technology as Metaphor, 9/28/95 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Language End-Game, The, 10/6/95 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Reflections on the Gutenberg Revolution, 10/9/95 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Books and Computers, 10/11/95 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Thoughts on Business and Creativity, 10/17/95 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Secret We Keep From the Young, A, 10/18/95 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Jane Marcet and Her Circle, 10/20/95 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Balance of Technology and the Flesh, The, 10/27/95 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Martin Luther, A Creation of Movable, Metal Type, 10/29/95 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Thoughts on Business and Creativity, 11/2/95 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Communication and the Evolution of Human Consciousness:, 11/14/95 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 12/6/95 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Romanticism and Revolution, 12/7/95 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Communication and the Evolution of Human Consciousness, 1/18/96 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Communication Revolution: A Promise of Social Upheaval, The, 2/7/96 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Thoughts on Living with Our Technologies, 2/9/96 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Terrifying Gift of Change, The, 2/18/96 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Lesion Within, The, 3/25/96 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Fine Madness: Sanity and Creativity, A, 3/26/96 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Eye of the Mind in 21st Century Engineering, The, 3/28/96 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Creativity and the End of Life: Aging and Suicide, 4/2/96 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Building a New Country, 4/9/96 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Looking for the Line Between Art and Technology, 4/23/96 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Looking for the Line Between Art and Technology, 4/23/96 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Metaphor of the Book, The, 4/26/96 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Talk for the High School for Engineering Professions, 5/1/96 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Some Remarks on Family Planning in History, 5/7/96 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Seeing on the Screen and Seeing In Our Minds, 5/22/96 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - What is a City? What is Houston?, 5/25/96 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Some Remarks on Family Planning in History, 6/5/96 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Seeing on the Screen and Seeing In Our Minds, 6/6/96 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Fine Madness: Sanity and Creativity, A, 6/8/96 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Reinventing Journals: Reinventing Knowledge, 6/21/96 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Fine Madness: Is It Possible to be Creative and Live a Normal Life?, A, 7/6/96 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - History is Written in the Book of Our Art, 7/25/96 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Telling Our Story: A Reflection on Journals and Knowledge, 8/5/96 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Many Faces of a University Scholar, The, 8/14/96 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - What is a City? What is Houston?, 8/20/96 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Jane Marcet and Her Circle: 19th Century Women and Technology, 9/19/96 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - What are the Engines of Our Ingenuity?, 9/25/96 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Lesion Within, The, 9/26/96 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Communication and the Evolution of Human Consciousness, 10/7/96 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Homo-Technologicus, 10/19/96 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - The Future of Technical Papers, 11/1/96 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Ilizarov and Visualization in 21st Century Technology, 11/9/96 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Creativity in Energy Systems, 11/14/96 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Of Action, Contemplation, and Sharing: Unity in Diversity, 11/21/96 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Mirrored By Our Machines, 11/21/96 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Future of Technical Papers, The, 12/5/96 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Medieval Church Technology and Science, 12/10/96 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Chemistry Seen Through the Eye of the Mind, 12/13/96 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Thoughts on Mind and Body, Gender and Medicine, 1/8/97 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Technology and Dying, 1/18/97 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Discussion with a Engineer/Historian, A, 1/27/97 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Highways of the 1930s: America in Transition, 1/28/97 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Dyslexia, The Hidden Edge, 2/2/97 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Seeing on the Screen and Seeing In Our Minds, 2/11/97 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Women in the Sky: Exploitation or Opportunity, 2/19/97 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Of Women and Airplanes: Exploitation or Opportunity?, 2/20/97 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Serving the Sick and Leveling the Pyramid, 2/27/97 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - EMCEE Script, 3/6/97 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Business and the Inventive Muse, 3/12/97 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reflections on Communications & Social Upheaval, 3/14/97 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Creativity in Giving and Receiving, 3/21/97 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - I Sell Here, Sir, What All the World Desires To Have - Power, 3/27/97 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Narrative and Medicine, 4/1/97 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Is Invention an Individual Art?, 4/3/97 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Narrative and Experience Transformed, 4/3/97 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Reflections on Language, 4/8/97 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Women in the Sky: Exploitation or Opportunity, 4/17/97 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Chance Favors Only the Prepared Mind: Part I, 4/20/97 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Chance Favors Only the Prepared Mind: Part III, 4/27/97 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Adam's Navel: Where is the First Person?, 5/1/97 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Decentralization Century: 1900 - 2000, The, 5/14/97 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Decentralization Century: 1900 - 2000, The, 5/14/97 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Women in the Sky: Exploitation or Opportunity?, 5/23/97 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Challenge of Managing Change, The, 6/20/97 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Children, Literacy, and the Computer, 6/30/97 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Language End Game, The, 7/9/97 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Earth's Age - Or Agelessness: Burnet, Hutton, Kelvin, and Adam's Navel, 7/14/97 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Reflections on Education as the Millennium Ends, 7/22/97 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Reflections on Communication and Change, 8/20/97 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Thoughts on Creativity, Failure, and Making Use of Change, 9/2/97 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Outsider Reflects on Indian Science & Technology, An, 9/6/97 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Lesion Within: Shaping Modern Medicine, The, 9/9/97 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Legacy of the Ecole Polytechnique, The, 9/17/97 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Swiss Festival, 10/5/97 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - On Learning To Fly: A New Look At An Old Story, 10/16/97 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Reflections On Science, Religion, and the Search For Reality: Part 1, 10/19/97 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - The Oldest Technology, 11/9/97 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Reflections on Education as the Millennium Ends, 11/20/97 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Innovation: A Dangerous Guest, 12/5/97 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - The Emergence of Printing In Colonial America, 1/17/98 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - The American Highway as an Element of Change, 1/28/98 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Invention: The Unwanted Daemon In Our Midst, 2/12/98 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Miscues: the Checkered History of Sustainability, 2/19/98 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Community and the Computer, 2/21/98 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Redeeming the Disorder of Illness, 3/2/98 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Trying to Ride the American Highway into the Future, 3/7/98 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - The Infinitely Shareable Property: Information in the New Millennium, 3/26/98 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - What People Said About Books in 1498, 4/7/98 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Community and the Computer, 4/9/98 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - The Language End Game, 4/15/98 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - All Things Considered, 4/16/98 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Business and the Inventive Muse, 4/21/98 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Before Oil; The Forgotten Energy Crisis, 4/23/98 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - The Light At the End of the Enlightenment, 4/25/98 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Business and the Inventive Muse, 4/26/98 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Two-D Screens in Three-D Reality: The Future of Ingenuity, 5/7/98 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Invisible Technology, 5/14/98 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Conversation on Science and Technology, 5/16/98 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Thoughts About Teaching the History of Technology and Science, 5/29/98 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Reflections on Corporate Singing, 6/6/98 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Finding the Door Into Technology: Women and Engineering Since 1639, 6/16/98 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Miscues: The Checkered History of Sustainability, 7/23/98 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 8/12/98 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Teaching Science and Technology's History, 8/19/98 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - The Polytechnic Legacy, 8/22/98 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - About Astronomy and Learning to See, 8/28/98 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Sewers: A Secret World, 9/3/98 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Looking for the Line Between Art and Technology, 9/11/98 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Learning to Live with the Internet, 9/19/98 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Redemption and Illness: Sanity and Creativity, 9/20/98 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 10/1/98 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - The Polytechnic Legacy, 10/15/98 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Creativity - An Enemy in our Midst, 10/20/98 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Trying to Ride the American Highway into the Future, 10/26/98 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - The Assyrian Legacy in American Culture, 11/7/98 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Fleeing the Creative Daemon, 11/17/98 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 11/20/98 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - The Polytechnic Legacy, 12/16/98 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - German Music and a Quiet Revolution, 12/20/98 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Women in Flight: Balloons, Parachutes, Airplanes…, 1/20/99 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Business and the Inventive Muse, 1/24/99 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - The Decentralization Century: 1999 - 2000, 2/1/99 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - A New Way of Seeing, 2/10/99 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - I Sell Here, Sir, What all the World Desires to Have - Power, 2/18/99 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - And Finally, Going to the Stars, 2/20/99 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Sharing and Retaining: An Essential Tension in Academic Libraries, 3/13/99 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Avoiding Learning, Avoiding Change, 3/23/99 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - I Engage, Then I See, Part I, 3/29/99 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Art and Technology: A Pair of Natural Bedfellows, 4/14/99 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Failure and Learning in 19th and 20th Century Construction, 4/28/99 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - A Concert of American Musical Invention, 5/16/99 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Women in flight: Balloons, Parachutes, Airplanes…, 5/20/99 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - What People Said About Books in 1498, 5/20/99 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - The Mind Outside the Body: The Last Great Transformation, 5/24/99 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Two-D Screens and Three-D Reality, 7/26/99 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Thoughts for the 1999 In-Service Day at Briarwood School, 8/11/99 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Worrying About Science Education in the New Millennium, 9/1/99 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Seeing the World in Three-Dimensional 1484 to 2001, 9/9/99 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - God, the Master Craftsmen: The Legacy of Technology and Medicine, 9/14/99 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - What People Said About Books in 1499, 10/16/99 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Light, 11/3/99 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Polytechnic Legacy, 11/4/99 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hymne to God, My God, In My Sicknesse, 11/7/99 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Who Was Jodocho De Frantia Biscantori?, 11/9/99 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - God, The Master Craftsman: Thoughts on Technology and Jubilee, 11/19/99 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Medicine In The New World, 11/17/99 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Iron: More Than Just A Material Perhaps A State of Mind, 12/7/99 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - War and Other Ways to Kill People: An Advent Reflection, 12/15/99 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Learning To Fly: Atavism and Gliding, 1/19/00 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Trying To Ride The American Highway Into The Future, 1/28/00 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - God The Master Craftsman: Thoughts On Technology and Jubilee, 2/2/00 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Narative and Healing: Telling Our Story…, 2/2/00 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Finding History Through Technology, 2/12/00 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Seeing Music As A New Technology in a New Land, 2/15/00 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Avoiding Learning; Avoiding Change, 2/22/00 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - The Polytechnic Legacy, 3/3/00 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - War and Other Ways To Kill People, 3/8/00 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Light At The End of the Enlightenment, 3/9/00 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Hymne To God My God, In My Sicknesse, 3/13/00 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 3/27/00 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - God The Master Craftman: Medieval Religion and Technology, 4/2/00 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - The Subtle Texture of Cooperation, 4/12/00 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Frankenstein, Faust, and Pygmalion, 4/20/00 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Reflections on Risk, New Technology and the Third Dimension, 4/28/00 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - What People Said About Books In 1498, 5/11/00 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Predicting A Future, 5/12/00 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Can We Redefine Learning?, 5/18/00 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Explorers Club: EMCEE Notes, 5/20/00 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The Wild Card: Creativity and Unpredictability, 5/23/00 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - And Finally, Going To The Stars, 6/2/00 (Box 8, Folder 37)